Nandan Hirpathak

Software Engineer at Microsoft

Summary

Currently working as a Software Engineer at Microsoft. Previously worked as a Software Engineer - Ad serving platform team at OpenX from Jan-2015 to June-2016. Interned at VMware from May-2014 to Aug-2014.

Graduated with Master's degree in Computer Science at University of Southern California (USC). Worked as a Student Research Assistant at USC - Information Sciences Institute in Distributed Systems/Cloud based project.

Interested in Software Development, Cloud Computing, Virtualization and Computer Networking.

Programming Languages: Java, C

Web technologies & Other Skills: HTML & CSS, JavaScript, SQL

Experience

Software Engineer at Microsoft

June 2016 - Present

Currently involved with designing and implementing a big data platform service leveraged for gaining insights about usage of office products and services

Software Engineer at OpenX

January 2015 - June 2016 (1 year 6 months)

- 1. Worked as a software engineer in ad serving platform group in an agile scrum methodology.
- 2. Involved in developing new features involved in serving digital ads specifically tied to ad tag library. Some of features include implementing web storage cache for ads, estimating location of an ad served on webpage and cascade it down the pipeline to provide better estimate for ad buyers.
- 3. Fire-fighting production related issues
- 4. Involved with deploying ad server components regularly

Software Engineer MTS Intern at VMware

May 2014 - August 2014 (4 months)

1. The Internship project focused on developing end-to-end web based application framework for providing more detailed test results information about various VMware products by analyzing logs and providing trending information, ability to identify failures during deployment and execution of VMware products easily and develop new user interface for displaying results.

- 2. Developed REST APIs which would interact with back end database to generate required amount of data depending on query received from front end
- 3. Technologies used: Java for back end, MongoDb as a database component and HTML5+Bootstrap CSS, Javascript and JQuery for front end

Research Student Assistant at Information Sciences Institute

May 2013 - December 2013 (8 months)

Software Engineer at Accenture

August 2010 - June 2012 (1 year 11 months)

BT Openreach Project (Feb-2012 to June-2012):

- 1. Worked in Functional Testing domain.
- 2. Designed and Implemented Functional and Regression test cases.
- 3. Involved in Test case data preparation.
- 4. Involved in Sanity Testing

BHP Billton Project (Dec-2010 to Jan-2012)

- 1. Worked on a project specific reporting tool for the creation of project transition reports and a customized service delivery tool which spanned ITIL processes.
- 2. Supported SAP system of the project by performing monitoring related activities including Forward Error Handling, Batch Job Monitoring, and IDOC Monitoring

Published a white paper on 'Data Quality through Cloud Computing' in Accenture. The paper describes how Cloud Computing platform is best suited for Data Quality Operations using a parallel programming paradigm: Map Reduce

Project Intern at Tata Consultancy Services

August 2009 - April 2010 (9 months)

Education

University of Southern California

Master's degree, Computer Science, 2013 - 2014

Maharashtra Institute of Technology, University of Pune

Bachelor's degree, Information Technology, 2006 - 2010

Nandan Hirpathak

Software Engineer at Microsoft



Contact Nandan on LinkedIn